Daniel Fernando Cubides (

■ About me

Transformational leader in software development and operations with experience building and empowering engineering teams to deliver and support PaaS/SaaS in hyper-growth environments. Passionate about growing technical leaders and building diverse, sustainable teams in an evolving Tech culture.

Skills

Technical leadership, Software Development Lifecycle (SDLC), Cultural Change, Mentorship, Risk Management, Cloud Adoption, Golang and Kubernetes

Experience		
April 2023	Software Engineering Manager	Telesign / Customer
		Engagement

At Telesign, I was responsible for:

- Leading a high-performing software engineering team building innovative communication services.
- Overseeing risk management in the development and deployment of software applications.
- Growing and mentoring a team of software engineers, fostering a culture of continual learning and improvement.
- Collaborating with multiple teams to build a strong understanding of our customers and their requirements.
- Bringing new ideas to life through drive, advocacy, and technical leadership.
- Actively promoting inclusion and diversity within our organization, cultivating a supportive and dynamic work environment.

The team tech stack: On-prem, AWS, Docker, react, Django, python, bash, CI/CD, DevOps methodologies.

Feb 2023 April 2022

Senior Software Engineering Manager

Twilio / Customer Engagement

At Twilio I was responsible for:

- Lead a software engineering team building API-based cluster automation services.
- Risk management.
- Grow and mentor a team of software engineers.
- Collaborate across multiple teams to build a strong understanding of our customers and their use cases.
- Bring new ideas to life through drive and advocacy.
- · Actively drive inclusion and diversity in our organization

The team tech stack: Kuberentes, Docker, Golang, python, bash, CI/CD, devops methodologies.

	el Fernando Cubides · http://www.dfcubidesc.com · dfcubidesc@gmail.com · $(+57)$ 316 2	268 2433	
April 2022 May 2021	Engineer Manager	Mo Technologies Fintec	
	As an Engineer Manager, I was responsible for projects and a team's activities and metrics to the department and then scopes out deliverables or work for the toverall technical excellence and quality of the product delivered by my team. Let team and works closely with the stakeholders and other areas to find the best poensure delivery in a timely manner. I supported activities that drive the system d best practices. The team tech stack: AWS ECS, AWS RDS, python Django, Multitenant arch Clean code, clean architecture, Agile methodologies.	eam. Ensures the eads the technical possible solution to esign and enforce	
May 2021 August 2020	Tech Lead	Commure / Healthcar	
	As a Software Engineer I was responsible for:		
	Build and ship secure, enterprise-grade software		
	Work with cutting-edge technologies		
	Have end-to-end ownership of projects throughout their life cycle		
	• Join our collaborative Engineering, Product, and Design team and provide a valued voice as we scale our team and culture		
	The team tech stack: Azure Kubernetes services, Postgres DB, Cockroach DB, Rust, Golang, Python, Multitenant architecture, CI/CD, Clean code, clean architecture and Agile methodologies.		
August 2020 January 2020		lin Jobs / Marketplac Acquired by Commure	
	As an Engineer Manager I was responsible for projects and a team's activities. Independently proposes goals to the department or functional leader and then scopes out deliverables or work for the team.		
January 2020 March 2019	_	lin Jobs / Marketplad Acquired by Commure	
	As a Backend Developer I should focus on creating and maintaining the API se tructure to support Merlin's products. Following the best practices in all the operation cycle. The team tech stack: GCP, Kubernetes, Postgres DB, Cockroach DB, Java, CI/CD, Clean code, clean architecture, Event Driven Architecture, Microservices Agile methodologies.	development and Golang, Python,	
 March 2020	Software Engineer	yxtera / CyberSecurit	
June 2017	I Design, plan and develop features related to DSB CLIENT's backend, System and data analysis, architecture, and design, Software development, configuration and customization. Document, design, and develop software components based or compatible with: Java, spring, play framework, javascript, scala, activeMQ, kafka, postgres, h2 and docker.		
December 2017 May 2015	Founder An	zus Development SA / service	
	I Lead the development of company strategy, Define the vision of the products and Manage the product backlog of the projects.		
June 2017 February 2014	Junior Software Architect	niversidad Nacional c	
	At this role I Lead the integration of the investigation department of the university operability platform, Design the web service catalogue and Design orchestration of	-	
EDUCATION			
2018 - 2020	Magister in Software Engineering	niversidad Nacional d Colombi	
	Thesis Proposal: Mapping Study in Adoption of Agile Methodologies. no degree		

2011 - 2016	Software Engineering	Universidad Nacional de
		Colombia
	Emphasis in Software Project Management	
Courses		
Certified	Management courses	Linkedin Learning
	Managing Virtual Teams	
	Leading at Distance	
	 Leadership Tips, Tactics, and Advice 	
	• The New Age of Risk Management Strategy for Business	
	Overcoming Complexity	
	How to Be an Effective Remote Manager	
	Building Resilience	
Certified, 80	Software evolution and maintenance	Universidad Nacional de

June 16, 2015 - July 10, 2015